You have to admit,
the Governor's plan is ingenious.
As long as he hoards
state food supplies...
Right, all these refugees
will work for crumbs.
And when he finally sells that food,
he'll make a fortune!
GOVERNOR'S COURT HOUSE,
CHEKIANG
The Shaolin monks are this way.
They won't be able to
resist our dim sum.
Honored visitors,
we've made you a midnight snack.
Chief Fox, if you cared less about food
and more about security,
you wouldn't need our help.
Just a taste. It's so delicious.
We have no time for dim sum.
Until we arrest the Iron Monkey,
keep your men out of the way!
Those Shaolin monks are so severe.
I should smack them,
but I'd rather have a snack.
I can't breathe.
Whose foot is in my face?
Hey, get back in here!
If the Iron Monkey sees you,
he'll find my treasure and steal it!
I just love the feel of gold.
You can bathe in it
after the Iron Monkey's caught.
Quick, someone's coming.
Governor, sir.
It's just me, sir.
I've brought you some shark-fin soup.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Keep our soup warm and don't eat any!
Taste even a drop and you will pay.
-I wouldn't dare, sir.
-There, on the roof!
To the east!
Not even a bird
can escape my new trap.
The Iron Monkey doesn't
stand a chance against us.
Are you sure about that?
Let's go.
Men! Over here!
I've got him.
Masters, it's us.
Out of our way, buffoons!
He wants to trick us.
Hold your positions.
I'm going to teach you a lesson.
You can't best the righteous!
You're righteous?
How can it be righteous
to defend a corrupt official?
He's in my house!
You're my favorite,
you can help me protect my jewels!
-Protect them yourself.
-Come back, my love!
Officer Cheng, unleash the trap!
You're not so smart. I finally got you!
Lower the net.
You were not harmed, sir?
You said my new trap couldn't fail.
Go find him!
-Check the roof.
-Yes, sir.
Shaolin punks.
Be careful up there!
I spent a fortune to get this post.
I'm not giving up the rewards.
Your Excellency,
I'm pleased to confirm the Iron Monkey
will go home empty-handed tonight.
What's this?
-My shark fin! I warned you!
-No, sir.
-Your salary is docked.
-In the fighting, soup hit my face...
Sir, the Iron Monkey has vanished.
Since you can't capture
a common criminal,
all of your salaries are forfeited to me.
I'm surrounded by imbeciles!
-Hey, which team do you belong to?
-Don't blink, or you'll miss the fun.
He's back!
Thanks for the donation,
Your Excellency.
You...
"The refugees certainly
appreciate your help.
"Give them some of the food
you've hoarded at the warehouse
"or you'll see more of me!"
They've raised the reward
for the Iron Monkey.
Again?
Chief Fox, we appreciate your offer
to introduce us to the Governor.
This could be a profitable relationship
for all of us.
Starting today,
a tribute for His Excellency.
With his consent,
our brothel will be a gold mine.
We've got fallen monks
to handle security
and desperate refugee girls
for entertainment.
A little something for you.
His Excellency is in a bad mood.
I must approach him carefully.
Hold your tribute.
If it's stolen, I can't afford to replace it.
Is it the Iron...
That name is bad luck.
He cost my men their salaries.
We can't even afford medical fees,
so your donation is a big help to us.
Come and thank Mr. Chan. Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Scratchy throat?
-Yes.
-Diarrhea?
-Yes! And I'm very tired.
All right, just give me your hand.
What do I suffer from?
You're oversexed
and your kidney is weak.
You eat too much shark fin.
This food makes you horny.
You are too weak for such rich food.
But shark fin is so delicious...
Honestly, I'm not that weak!
You will need medicine.
-Your fee will be 100 taels.
-100 taels?
-I don't have that much, Doctor.
-Don't worry, sir.
I won't charge you anything.
Thank you.
That's outrageous!
My medicine should be free, too.
You're a rich man.
Your medicine is expensive.
If you can't afford it,
I can give you cheaper medicine.
I can afford it. Pay him.
-He loves to take his medicine.
-Thank you.
-Doctor.
-You look well.
-Dr. Yang.
-Chief Fox.
Look at all these patients.
Are they all refugees?
They come from as far as Haining.
Some have been walking
for three days.
On top of it all, many have
symptoms of the plague.
Plague?
That's horrible.
Miss Orchid.
Obstipantia, ginseng...
Check the list.
Don't take the wrong herb.
-Miss Orchid.
-Chief Fox, what's wrong with you?
Nothing yet. But these sick people
are making me nervous.
I heard the Iron Monkey was arrested.
Is it true?
I had that Monkey in my
"Crushing Serpent" hold.
He couldn't move! I was about
to give him a "Flying Dragon" punch...
-Are you hurt?
-Oh, my shoulder!
It must have been great
to finally catch him.
So many of my men were in danger...
I had to let him go.
You always have a new move
to catch the Iron Monkey.
But you always release him.
You're giving him too many chances.
I must owe him something
from a previous life.
He's tortured me since I arrived here.
But one day,
I'll tear the coward's mask off!
Chief Fox, look at your hand...
Hot! Hot!
What delicate skin!
Do you like to be touched?
My brothel could use a soft touch...
-Get lost!
-You bitch!
Find your hookers elsewhere.
Oh, Chief Fox?
We are friends, please forgive me.
This clinic is under my protection.
I won't tolerate indecent behavior here!
Chief Fox, I am dishonored.
Allow me to save face.
100 taels of gold should clear things.
How dare you bribe me out in the open!
-Take him to the jail.
-How dare you! I'm a powerful man.
Who will never meet the Governor
without my introduction.
Go!
Chief Fox, thank you very much.
Take this ointment for your men.
Apply it to their wounds.
-Soon they will feel better.
-Thank you.
Goodbye.
I've been chasing the Iron Monkey
day and night. I'm going to drop soon.
-I hope he stays home tonight.
-Get some rest.
-Good morning, Dr. Yang.
-Good morning.
You don't think
he could be the Iron Monkey?
Everyone looks like
the Iron Monkey to me.
Add more bark. It'll taste better.
But the soup already tastes like a tree.
What was that?
It's real gold from the Iron Monkey.
Give it to me! I'm in charge.
Who threw that at me?
"Don't be greedy."
I'm not greedy.
I'll share it with everyone.
-Thank you, Iron Monkey.
-The building is falling down!
-No, it's gold from the Iron Monkey.
-Bless you, Iron Monkey.
No slacking off!
There's plenty of refugees
where you came from.
I can replace you tomorrow.
Faster, or do you want another beating?
-But we haven't eaten all day.
-That reminds me...
Back to work,
or it's back to the gutter I found you in.
A dead rat!
-Who threw that at me?
-You're disgusting!
-The Iron Monkey really exists.
-Iron Monkey!
Would you like some help?
Not even this downpour
can discourage you.
You might get hurt without me.
The Governor hates you
even more than he loves money.
It's expensive to feed nine wives.
Vegetables and bean curd again.
I'm sick of it!
You're the Governor,
yet we eat like peasants.
If I hadn't hidden my gold so well,
you'd have nothing to eat.
I'd be better off in a brothel.
You think it's easy
to support the nine of you?
I suppose you want me to sell
some food from the state warehouse
-and charge our refugees a fortune.
-Then you could throw us a feast.
All you care about is eating.
You can help me.
But, sir, you've already taken my salary.
I don't need your tiny salary.
I want you
to open the warehouse for me!
Sir, it's a letter from the capitol!
Master, is it a promotion?
Congratulations!
The Royal Minister?
He's coming about the Iron Monkey.
He wouldn't blame you
for anything, would he?
Why are you still here?
Capture that Monkey!
Arrest anyone who could possibly
be the Iron Monkey.
-Anyone and everyone.
-Yes, sir!
-What do you call that stance?
-The "Monkey's Fist."
-"Monkey's Fist?"
-Yes.
-Come on, let's go!
-What did I do?
We know you're the Iron Monkey.
-You look like a monkey. Arrest him.
-But all I did was sneeze.
You sneezed like a monkey.
Take him in!
-Crushed monkey powder...
-What are you selling?
-Don't mention the word "monkey."
-Take a look yourself.
You won't tell us?
You must be up to something!
You're coming with us!
-Hold tighter.
-Yes, Dad.
Dad.
You're old enough
to walk on your own now.
Recite the herb list.
Chiretta, good for blood.
Ginseng, good for respiration.
Crocodile, to cure arthritis.
Lizard, for poison.
Tsin-tsi...
To cure swelling, you fool.
Tsin-tsi, to cure swelling, you fool!
-Sir.
-Master Wong.
-Your herbs are all ready.
-Good. Send them to the inn.
We're leaving
for Foshan in the morning.
Certainly.
That's all you've made
from a whole day's work?
You think this is a charity home?
If you can't earn any money
for me, steal some.
-Who did that?
-Fei-hung.
You're too old to play with this.
Shoot at me?
Go to the inn
and practice your footwork.
Four hours minimum.
Go pick his pocket.
What are you doing
picking pockets at your age?
I'll never do it again, sir.
I'll let you go this time
but don't do it again.
You're lucky!
I have to drill for four hours.
-What's wrong with drilling?
-What's wrong with stealing?
Do I have to show you?
He's good.
Could he be the Iron Monkey?
Maybe.
Hey, you, come with us!
He stole my stuff.
I didn't see that, but I did see you fight!
Move! Hurry up!
Don't act so innocent.
Behind those innocent faces,
one of you is that devil, Iron Monkey.
Confess!
This doesn't have to be unpleasant.
I don't wish to keep you all here.
I only want the Iron Monkey.
You may all go home just as soon as
the Iron Monkey shows himself.
Sir, that monkey is flashing
his butt at you!
How dare you disgrace this court?
I hate indecency.
Take him to the dungeon.
Sir, you can eat
monkey's brains tonight.
Don't let my wives know.
If no one confesses,
you will each be fined 50 taels.
Only 50 taels?
What punishment is appropriate?
This is serious.
We should fine them 500 taels.
Or do these cretins think
it should be more?
-Oh, no, sir.
-Have mercy.
If you have no money,
we have another penalty.
Iron Monkey, where are you now?
A real hero would show himself,
or do you prefer humiliation?
Don't you look so very conflicted?
Torture him!
Dad!
You can't do this without any proof!
-How dare you?
-Is he telling you how to govern?
You will learn
to respect my court, little boy.
Brand him now!
-He's just a kid.
-Hold it, Officer.
Chief Fox, do you want
to be tortured, too?
Your Excellency, he is only a boy.
He cannot be the Iron Monkey.
He is only a boy
and cannot pay the fine.
No money! Full penalty!
Don't move.
Release these innocent people!
Release them?
The only reason they're here is
to get you out in the daylight!
You're trapped!
Riflemen, take your positions!
Kill him!
He's outside. Go after him!
Your actions prove
you are not fit to govern.
Sir, you're missing an eyebrow.
What kind of monster
would shave my eyebrow?
Iron Monkey, you're no hero.
These innocent people wouldn't
be here if it weren't for you.
Oh, my foot!
Why is he fighting Iron Monkey?
Set the ladders now.
It's a kid!
-Fei-hung, are you all right?
-I'm fine.
You were great.
-My father is well known in...
-Quiet, Son.
-Thank you.
-Please.
He's as powerful as the Iron Monkey.
Sir, the Iron Monkey's appearance
proves we are innocent.
May we leave now?
No! You might be his partner.
Until he is caught,
no one will be released.
-Very wise, sir.
-Sir, be merciful! Please, let us go!
Sir, Wong Kei-ying
will arrest the Iron Monkey.
You can let them go.
-Are you Wong Kei-ying from Foshan?
-Yes, sir.
Nice to meet you.
Wong Kei-ying! He's famous!
More famous than me?
Wong Kei-ying,
I'll be merciful this time.
You have seven days
to arrest the Iron Monkey.
In the meantime, we will hold your son.
My son?
So you won't leave town.
If you can't catch the Iron Monkey
you will join your son in the dungeon.
Dismissed!
-Am I going to be alone?
-I'll arrest him soon.
-Don't worry, I'll keep an eye on him.
-Thank you.
Set them free.
He's helping the Governor
catch the Iron Monkey.
What a bastard!
Hot, delicious noodles.
A bowl of noodles for you?
You'll love them. My mother's recipe.
I'll have a bowl, please.
Are you the one
who fought with the Iron Monkey?
-I am.
-Shame on you.
I won't sell you anything! Go!
-Why?
-Why? Ask a fortuneteller why.
-I'd like two buns, please.
-I don't sell buns to your kind.
My kind?
I can pay!
I wouldn't sell dirt to you!
-Nonsense.
-Wong Kei-ying is robbing me!
Help! Wong Kei-ying is robbing me!
Bastard!
-Do you want a bun? Five taels each.
-That's expensive!
That's cheap.
I'm risking my life selling to you.
I quit! I'm sorry!
Hot buns.
I'll take 20.
Thanks.
Are you hungry, sir?
That bun is dirty.
You must be very hungry!
I'm lucky to have this.
I haven't eaten for two days.
No one here will sell me any food.
It can be rough for strangers here.
Don't eat that.
Why don't you come in
and have some soup?
Soup!
I'm so hungry. Just the thought of soup
makes my stomach upset.
If you had some rice...
-Master Wong, how are you doing?
-Not too bad.
Be patient, it'll be ready soon.
Master Wong,
we grow a special chili here.
It's called "Sweating."
Just a taste
and you'll be dripping with sweat.
Try some.
It's terrific.
Are you thirsty?
Save some room for soup, all right?
I only had a sip of water
to cleanse my palate
so I can taste your soup better.
Use an apron the next time
you "cleanse your palate."
Miss Orchid. Let me help you.
I'll make you some
quick Cantonese dishes.
That looks delicious!
Master Wong, you're quite a cook.
My wife passed away,
so I do all kinds of housework.
Master Wong, we are honored
to have you cook for us.
It's just simple Cantonese food.
A taste of the North here in the South.
Let me show you
how we shred noodles here.
The first shred is God's blessing.
The second, for good luck.
The third, peace and prosperity.
Good!
Welcome to our home.
To new friends.
-Cheers!
Master Wong, is something wrong?
I'm thinking of my boy.
Your feast is delicious,
but my young son is
in the Governor's prison.
I don't know if he's eaten at all.
Dr. Yang, have you heard
of the Iron Monkey?
I've heard the rumors.
Are you looking for him?
If I catch him, I'll chop his head off!
Are you his enemy?
The Governor will hold my son
until I arrest the Iron Monkey.
If I can catch him,
my boy and I can go home to Foshan.
If I don't...
What's your son's name?
-Wong Fei-hung.
I won't bother you further.
The sooner I catch the Iron Monkey,
the sooner I see my son.
Dr. Yang, Miss Orchid,
I'll repay you for your help one day.
Good night. Good luck.
-Miss Orchid...
-I know. You want to save the boy now.
That dungeon is no place for a boy.
We'll take the medicine box.
He may need it.
Give us some water,
we haven't had any for days.
Shut up in there!
Why does the child sleep all day?
Are you all right? Can you hear me?
Now you have to drink.
-Chief Fox!
-Open the gate.
Wong Fei-hung, you've got a visitor.
His forehead is hot
and his mouth is dry.
Dr. Yang, what's wrong with him?
He can't stay here anymore.
It's lucky we caught this.
His plague may be contagious.
Plague?
-It's not that bad. Don't panic.
-We're not panicking.
The Royal Minister arrives in two days.
I don't have time to watch the boy.
I don't know what to tell his father.
Chief Fox,
the conditions are too poor here.
Let him stay with me.
Sorry to trouble you.
You all keep your mouths shut
about this!
-We will.
-We will. Just get him out of here.
Dad's umbrella...
Master Wong.
Come and have a midnight snack.
Sounds good.
There's no table here,
but the food is good.
The view's not bad, either.
Help yourself.
Chief Fox, thank you
for taking care of my son.
I'm happy to help, but for all our sakes,
capture the Iron Monkey soon.
With the Royal Minister coming,
the Governor's running us ragged.
He's a bit on edge.
Would he harm my son?
You catch the Iron Monkey for me
and I'll protect your son for you, okay?
The Iron Monkey?
Wait for me!
Which one of you is the Iron Monkey?
I'm Chief Fox. You're under arrest.
The bastards kidnapped a woman!
-"Shaolin Fist"?
-You use Shaolin kung fu!
So what?
Are you students of Shaolin?
A monk?
The "Super Eagle's Claw"!
You're a student
of the Shaolin traitor, Hin-hung?
We Shaolin are now devoted
to the Royal Minister.
Dad, look out!
Here comes the Iron Monkey.
Be careful!
Fei-hung.
It's you.
Tell Dad I'm all right.
The old one worries
about the young one.
The young one worries
about the old one.
As it should be.
I know who you are.
What did he say?
Ask him when he wakes up.
Miss Orchid, your clients are waiting!
My son?
My son.
It was just another mouth to feed.
It's time for you to earn your keep.
Back to work.
You want to join your bastard?
Bitch!
I will redeem Miss Orchid.
This is worth more than her dead body.
You can't come in here.
This is the Governor's house.
Shit! Where is that little bureaucrat?
Hey! You can't go in there!
You must have an invitation
to see His Excellency.
Idiot! The Royal Minister
doesn't need an invitation.
Don't hit these fools with the Royal Fan.
Royal Fan?
I remember this house very well,
but I didn't see you on my last visit.
Are you new here?
I only arrived here two years ago.
Did you check his identity?
I didn't dare! I'm just a junior officer.
You're splashing too much.
Give me a kiss!
Let's see that eyebrow.
You'll have a crooked eyebrow
if you keep squirming.
Make me look good
for my subjects, sweetie.
-Who are you?
-Shouldn't you be expecting me?
It's the middle of the day
and you're playing in the bath?
Your Excellency.
I need to see your books.
Put some clothes on.
Yes, sir.
Hurry, I'm a very busy man.
The Royal Fan?
-Your Excellency.
-Is that really the Royal Fan?
I had the honor of being struck by it!
Have you seen his official seal?
I'm just the head of security.
I didn't dare ask.
You're useless.
Get my clothes!
You call yourself a governor?
My six-year-old daughter
keeps better records.
Sir, please forgive me.
Pick it up.
Sir, I'm afraid I have to see
your official seal.
You're green.
That's why you don't know me.
Bring me my briefcase.
What happened to all my papers?
What's this?
The Iron Monkey!
Iron Monkey? You must be joking!
The Iron Monkey is no joke, sir.
He's been terrorizing our province
for years.
Why do you think I'm here, moron?
What I want to know is
how could he have entered
the home of the Governor
undetected by your men?
Please forgive me.
Someone here switched my papers
with this drawing!
Call the court to order!
You all look innocent, but one of you
is the Iron Monkey. Confess now!
-Who stole the seal?
-Hand it over!
Don't pretend to be pitiful.
Your Excellency, a fine is in order...
I'm a kind-hearted minister.
I love my citizens.
You can't be kind-hearted
to these imbeciles.
He sounds familiar to me.
He sounds like you.
It proves you are his equal.
Who will confess?
I'll have to teach you a lesson!
Very wise of you, sir.
Teach these men some respect!
Chief Fox!
-Sir.
-I know it's you.
Give Governor Cheng 30 lashes!
-Sir, it's an order! I can't refuse.
-Do it now!
Wait...
Wait, I may have something
that can help!
What?
Ouch!
Your Excellency,
do these "documents" help?
It is wise of you to find
these "documents" so quickly.
Come over here.
Your Excellency, me again?
-Sir...
-You're too smart a man
to be wasting your talents
in this poor town.
Thank you, sir.
I'll deploy you to a wealthier province.
Choose it yourself.
Choose it myself?
I can go anywhere?
I'm going to be rich.
It's almost worth the beating.
Prepare for our return trip.
Yes, sir.
-Governor Cheng.
-Yes, sir.
The Emperor does not want
his public suffering.
My report would be more favorable
if you could help him.
Thank you, sir.
I officially declare the warehouse open!
Only a bit more. The Governor
doesn't want to release too much.
I've chosen my new post in Canton.
Do you have any advice
for dealing with the court?
That's enough. Take it to the square.
Treat life in politics like a dream.
Don't take things too seriously,
and you will always be at ease.
Right, sir. My regards to the Emperor.
Ginseng is good for respiration.
Crocodile to cure arthritis.
Tsin-tsi is good... You fool.
Stop hitting me!
Show me your tongue.
Come on, show me your tongue.
You have a slight fever.
Dr. Yang hasn't returned.
Let me give you some medicine.
If you still have a fever tonight,
come back to see us.
Thank you, Miss Orchid.
"I borrowed some pills to raise money.
"When I find my dad,
I will pay you back."
Ladies and gentlemen,
I lost my dad here.
I am short of money to return home.
I've no choice
but to sell this life-saving pill.
Whatever you can pay is good.
Your slingshot saved us.
We'll help you.
Let us at him.
So, your dad roughed us up,
but where is he now?
Wong Fei-hung doesn't need his dad.
Wong Fei-hung, run!
He's headed for the cafés.
Watch out, coming through!
Nice moves. Well done.
Thank you.
Watch out. Hot water.
Some hot water for you!
That was a really expensive table!
You little bastard!
Give me that.
Sir, this will pay for your table.
-Enough?
-It's more than enough!
This'll make us even.
My kung fu is pretty good.
Wong Fei-hung, you're great!
Do you accept any students?
I'm not qualified to teach.
Hey, you punks!
Which one of you is Wong Fei-hung?
-That's him.
-This is your "dragon"?
He's not even a worm.
He's too small to fight.
I may not be big,
but I'm not afraid of you.
You should be, you little show-off!
Quite powerful!
At least I don't show off my butt.
I'll race you.
You can't even follow me.
If I can't beat you down,
I'll give up martial arts.
Then give up now.
Did you really quit so easily?
Over here, show-off.
I'm warning you,
you're going to hurt yourself.
Stop toying with him.
Shut up! He was lucky.
What was that?
Stone!
Fei-hung, get up.
Come on.
Why did you sneak away?
I'm sorry, but I have to find my dad.
Maybe I can help you. Let's go.
Welcome, Your Excellency!
Summon the Governor.
Summon the Governor...
Summon me?
Is the Royal Minister back again?
Who does this monk think he is?
Fine him, and put him in the dungeon.
That's no way to greet
the Royal Minister!
You're the Royal Minister?
Another one!
I have to see your official seal this time.
I hope this meets with your approval!
He's not an impostor.
Your Excellency.
I'm hungry now. Bring me some lunch.
Yes.
Prepare some vegetarian dishes
for the Minister.
Yes.
His Excellency would like chicken
and shark-fin soup.
Of course. Of course.
The rod is blind, it seeks all injustice.
A strong force flows
from north to south.
Fei-hung, your turn.
Seek the way.
"Fisherman's Paddle."
"Double Flight from The Sea."
Old branches on the ground,
open both up and down.
You enjoy teaching him.
He reminds me of myself
when I was younger.
Before they murdered your father?
The boy is very talented.
You can't bring your father back.
No, but I can teach this boy
a little of what my father taught me.
Fei-hung, come.
They should be together.
-Thank you.
-My pleasure.
Look at you.
Don't worry, Dad. I was good.
I haven't let you down.
Good! Now if only we could go home.
Thank you for rescuing my son.
My pleasure.
Please.
They say even more refugees
are headed here.
Then the Iron Monkey
will be out tonight.
Fei-hung, here.
Fei-hung, what's that?
You can't eat roast duck.
Let go!
He is still recovering
and should be on a diet.
Dr. Yang, you eat it.
With the medicine I gave him,
he doesn't need to diet.
We monks are austere.
A simple diet is best for good health.
Fei-hung is still young.
Roast duck is so greasy.
His stomach is too weak
for greasy food.
It's better to eat less.
Don't look at it that way.
And how should I look at it?
He hasn't had an appetite until today.
Now, his hunger has returned.
It doesn't matter what he eats
so long as he has an appetite.
We'll be here all night
if you keep quarrelling.
I'm sorry.
You're supposed to be a monk?
How can you steal all nine of my wives?
"Don't take politics too seriously,
and you will always be at ease."
No one can escape death, my love,
but you left me all alone.
I pray you will forgive what I have to do.
I can't afford to bury you
unless I sell myself.
You don't have to do that.
Take this money
and bury your husband.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
I'll bury you instead!
It's a trap.
The Royal Minister will have your hide.
Surrender.
You can't handle the two of us.
You work for the Royal Minister?
Of course.
The Minister controls
all the Shaolin monks now.
Unbelievable...
You've ruined the Shaolin Society.
The "Virgin's Sword" stance.
You may be ugly,
but I doubt you're a virgin.
Do you think you should wear white?
Too bad this is the dull side.
Pathetic!
That's what you call excellence?
I'll show you excellence!
Shaolin "Buddha's Palm."
You're powerful for an ordinary man!
And wise... You know
the poisoned "Buddha's Palm!"
It's nothing special.
I'll show you my "Nothing Special."
You won't last 30 minutes
before the poison kills you.
Iron Monkey?
"Shaolin Fist"?
The Shaolin traitor?
I'm the Royal Minister, Hin-hung, now.
You betrayed the Shaolin to become
the Emperor's henchman.
Birds live for food. Men live for fortune.
Preach that to your dead colleagues.
-Tell me your name.
-I'm Wong Kei-ying.
Wong Kei-ying, your kung fu is unique.
You're right...
I invented the "Shadow Kick."
I'm going to kick you into the shadows.
Are you all right?
What happened to you?
Bring me the needles.
I was hit by the "Buddha's Palm."
You must release the poisoned blood.
Quickly.
Now, get the antidote.
Centipede.
Scorpion tail.
Viper.
Lizard.
Wake up.
Please, you have to help me.
Do I need anything else?
Wake up...
Dr. Yang.
Are you okay, Dad?
Fei-hung, I'm hurt. Find Dr. Yang now.
What's going on?
The Iron Monkey?
What are you doing, Fei-hung? Let go!
He isn't the Iron Monkey!
How dare you confront your father?
Master Wong.
Is Dr. Yang the Iron Monkey?
I just want
to inspect his wound, silly kid.
I haven't forgotten
what you've done for us.
"The Buddha's Palm!"
Poison against poison.
It's a brilliant treatment.
Extraordinary.
-Fei-hung, get the pen and ink.
-Yes, Dad!
-Poison will change...
-"Poison will change..."
-...poison for blood.
-"...poison for blood."
Release the blood
and revitalize the soul.
"Release the blood
and revitalize the soul."
Your fate is in the palm of my hand.
-Emergency aid.
-"Emergency aid."
-Single chance for life.
-"Single chance for life."
Every breath
brings you closer to death.
Hurry up. Cure him.
The Iron Monkey and Wong Kei-ying
are both hurt.
Check all the clinics.
Arrest those who are hurt!
-Yes, sir!
This medicine can work
for many diseases.
But it is a most powerful antidote
for all kinds of poisons.
It's amazing!
I would never have thought
to treat poison with poison.
So, what do you plan to do now?
I don't know what to do.
I can't turn you in.
But if I don't make an arrest,
the Governor will
track me down in Foshan.
Now you know
why we need an Iron Monkey.
Our province was corrupted
back when my father was a courtier.
My father exposed his colleagues
to the Governor,
but he'd known all along.
That day, my father didn't come home.
Maybe someday,
we'll have honest officials
and the Iron Monkey can retire.
-Who is it?
-Chief Fox!
-Where is Dr. Yang?
-He's out.
Where's Wong Fei-hung?
He is with Dr. Yang.
Shit!
The Royal Minister
wants them arrested.
Why?
Don't play games.
I know more than you think.
-Master Wong...
-I heard.
What am I supposed to do now?
Let's go back to Foshan.
You have to go home alone tonight.
If I leave, too,
the Governor's men will follow.
I'll come home when it's safe.
No matter what, Son,
I promise, I will make it back.
Yes, Dad.
Fei-hung, you must be strong now.
I understand.
A strong man sheds blood
before he sheds tears.
Don't worry, Dad.
Dr. Yang, please watch after my dad.
Don't worry about me, Dad.
Fei-hung, have you forgotten
my words?
You must be strong!
What did I just say to you?
"A strong man sheds blood
before he sheds tears."
Master Wong, we must go now.
Okay.
Don't worry. I'll take care of Fei-hung.
Fei-hung, go on. I'll answer it.
Open the door!
Now this is a pretty girl!
You're supposed to be a monk.
Where's your respect for tradition?
Some monks can appreciate
pretty girls.
We can all enjoy tonight.
You don't want our lives to be empty?
"Grappling Hands"?
Her kung fu is strong!
Maybe the Iron Monkey is a woman!
I won't be humiliated by a woman.
Sleeping powder.
It's working.
Now we're going to have some fun.
I hope you're in the mood
to entertain tonight.
Go to hell, you bastards.
You aren't monks. You're a disgrace!
This little boy has a death wish!
Get out of here.
"Carry the Bow" and "Shoot the Moon."
"Monkey's Rod."
"Double Flight from the Sea."
"Fisherman's Paddle."
What are you chanting?
Too many stances.
Don't let his stances disturb you.
"Rod that Sweeps Away Injustice."
Very powerful.
"A Strong Force Flows
from North to South."
Don't let him chant! No chanting.
"The Top Turns over the Sky."
"The Bottom Turns under the Earth."
-"Fix the Body."
-Fix what?
Fix your head.
Fix your toes.
Left, right, left, right, left.
Chin.
"Golden Snake Goes into the Hole."
"Golden Snake Comes out of the Hole."
Fix the chin again.
Old witch, how dare you bully a kid?
Why not?
No "Shadow Kick."
Rebel monks took Fei-hung.
What?
Are you all right?
Orchid, what happened to you?
Miss Orchid?
Orchid.
Tell us where your father is.
You're lucky he's not here,
or he'd Shadow Kick your bald head!
You won't be so tough
after we finish with you!
If we kill him, sir,
we'll never find Wong Kei-ying.
Shut up, lackey.
I'm the head of security here.
How dare you?
Chief Fox...
It's a trap!
Let the boy go.
What do you care about a kid?
What do you care?
Hin-hung, these are for you!
Catch Fei-hung!
The "Flying Sleeves"!
Come to me!
I don't care which of you is the
Iron Monkey, you're both going to die.
Kill them now.
Straight to Hell!
Oh, no, you don't!
Hello, Miss Orchid.
You will all die now!
The ugly virgin again?
Get the boy out of here.
Sir, help me...
I can handle him. Get out of here!
"Flying Sleeves"?
Why not "Buddha's Palm"?
You were lucky to survive,
but a smarter man
would have stayed away.
Your sect killed my father.
Let's make it a family tradition.
Hurry up!
Stay where you are!
This game is over.
You will never escape me.
And you'll never rest easy, you traitor.
You're no better than
that common criminal, the Iron Monkey.
You have no right to call me a traitor.
Stop pretending to be righteous.
If we didn't have vermin like you,
there would be no need
for the Iron Monkey.
Come here.
Over here, traitor.
Fei-hung! Stay back!
Up to the poles!
Dad, get down before it's too late!
Go for his legs.
Grab my hand!
Iron Monkey, come over here.
The pole is breaking.
Balance on the ends!
Having trouble standing?
Don't worry about us.
That pole won't last long.
They won't even find your ashes.
Flip me into the air.
Throw us the rods!
Catch.
Dad.
Everything's okay.
I didn't think I was going to make it.
We don't want to be found here.
Let's go.
Master Wong,
when will we meet again?
Why don't you visit us in Foshan?
Miss Orchid, you'll come.
I wanted to say goodbye.
Chief Fox, we almost missed you.
Sorry, but I'm busy
chasing the Iron Monkey.
The new Governor has arrived.
Can we hope for a just one?
We have to say goodbye.
Fei-hung, let's go.
Safe travels, my friends.